<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Hell Court Development Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Development blog for Hell Court]]></description><link>http://hellcourtgame.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 20:39:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hellcourtgame.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Code Foundations]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="/images/object-pool-code.png" alt="Object Pool Code"><p>When I was programming Hell Court for Ludum Dare, I didn&#x2019;t start with any code. That&#x2019;s probably why the resulting code ended up being a mess. That and the 72 hours limit. So before I&#x2019;ll continue working on the game, I decided to write some foundations. Here&#x2019;s what I ended with.</p>]]></description><link>http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/code-foundations</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/code-foundations</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About Hell Court]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hell Court is a game I originally made for <a href="http://ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-33/?action=preview&amp;uid=33094">Ludum Dare #33</a>. The theme was &#x201C;You are the monster&#x201D;. Here&#x2019;s what the original was and what the full version will be.</p>
<h3 id="origins">Origins</h3>
<p>The idea behind the game was that you are a <strong>devil in a hell dungeon</strong>. Humans come down there to <strong>pay for their sins</strong>. Every human has a random number of randomly generated sins. You have to deal appropriate amount of mental and physical pain based on human&#x2019;s sins. You also have minions - skeletons that do funny things. Then some weird contraptions like a healing table and a flamer.</p>
<p>I received a very valuable feedback on the game. Pretty much everybody liked the game, some players had great ideas about how to make the game better. So I decided to continue working on the game and make it into a full version.</p>
<h3 id="full-version">Full Version</h3>
<p>The platform element in the original version was not necessary. It sometimes even got in the way of playing the game. So in the full version, there will only be a basic movement to move around the level but nothing more. You also won&#x2019;t control just one minion, but you will be able to possess any one of them.</p>
<p>The full version will focus on the management element of the gameplay. The game will mostly be about <strong>managing a successful hell dungeon</strong>, dealing with humans effectively. There will be several types of sins and more ways to deal pain.</p>
<p>Possessing minions won&#x2019;t be the only way to operate your dungeon. You will also be able to assign commands to you minions. You will be able to tell them what to do with humans, where to move, etc. I&#x2019;m also thinking about allowing loops and conditionals in the commands. That way you could automate your dungeon.</p>
<p>So now you know what to expect. Stay tuned for more development blog posts.</p><p>Hell Court is a game I originally made for <a href="http://ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-33/?action=preview&amp;uid=33094">Ludum Dare #33</a>. The theme was &#x201C;You are the monster&#x201D;. Here&#x2019;s what the original was and what the full version will be.</p>]]></description><link>http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/about-hell-court</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/about-hell-court</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Website is Online]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Today I&#x2019;ve finally built and published the Hell Court development blog. This is <strong>the first blog post</strong>.</p>
<p>This website is a development blog for Hell Court, my upcoming game. Hell Court is about managing hell dungeon. Humans come down there to be punished for their sins. It&#x2019;s up to you to decide how to deal with them.</p>
<p>I will post <strong>progress updates</strong> on the game to this blog. It will contain the newest information, code samples, images, etc. Later I plan to add my <strong>Github milestones</strong> to this website. I use them to track progress and information about them will be displayed here.</p>
<p>I tried to keep the website as simple as possible. Currently, there are no client-side scripts and few CSS stylesheets. The website is built using <a href="http://www.metalsmith.io/">Metalsmith</a>, a cool plugin based static site generator. The build files are then hosted on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>. The source code is hosted on <a href="https://github.com/chuckeles/hellcourtgame.com">Github</a>.</p>
<p>There are still things to add to the website, such as an about page, newsletter, gallery, etc. These will be added throughout time.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading! If you&#x2019;d like to know more, write to me on <a href="https://twitter.com/9chuckeles9">Twitter</a>. If you like this blog, go ahead and tell others!</p><p>Today I&#x2019;ve finally built and published the Hell Court development blog. This is <strong>the first blog post</strong>.</p>]]></description><link>http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/website-is-online</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://hellcourtgame.com/blog/website-is-online</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>